<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Otago Repository for Core Analysis</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Otago Repository for Core Analysis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Form</title>
      <link>/form/form/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/form/form/</guid>
      <description> Should you wish to work at the facility please fill out the form below. if you have any queries please contact Bob Dagg
email: orca@otago.ac.nz (note: have requested a role based email) phone: 021 279 5815
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facilities</title>
      <link>/equipment/equipment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/equipment/equipment/</guid>
      <description> The Otago Coring Repository has the following facilities and equipment:
 Geotek MultiSensor Core Logger iTrax XRF core scanner Geotek Core Splitter Multiple Refrigerated Containers for Core Storage Bench space with access to natural light for visual core logging  Other facilities available for analysis of cores and core samples at the University of Otago include
 The Otago Paleomagnetic Research Facility located in the Geology Department. This facility contains  Cryogenic Magnetometer located in a magnetic feild free room MFK1 Kappabridge Vibrating Sample Magnetometer  Laser Grain Size Analyser located in the Geography Department  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geotek Multi-Sensor Core Logger</title>
      <link>/equipment/geotekmscl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/equipment/geotekmscl/</guid>
      <description>The Geotek MSCL situated at ORCA is an instrument for gathering data in an automated and quality-controlled way. The parameters that can be measured are
 P-wave velocity; Gamma density; Magnetic susceptibility using both loop and point sensors; Electrical resistivity; Colour linescan imaging including RGB data at sub-millimeter resolution Colour spectrophotometry  Measurements are typically made at a 5mm Resolution with the exception of the loop magnetic susceptibility on whole cores which is measured at a 20mm Resolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links</title>
      <link>/links/link/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/links/link/</guid>
      <description>Intergrated Ocean Drilling Program The International Ocean Discovery Program (IODP) is an international marine research collaboration that explores Earth’s history and dynamics using ocean-going research platforms to recover data recorded in seafloor sediments and rocks and to monitor subseafloor environments. IODP depends on facilities funded by three platform providers with financial contributions from five additional partner agencies. Together, these entities represent twenty-three nations whose scientists are selected to staff IODP research expeditions conducted throughout the world’s oceans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rates for Hire</title>
      <link>/rates/rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/rates/rates/</guid>
      <description>Geotek Internal University Use: $ 50/hr, min charge of 4 hours
External Research Use: $80/hr (non commercial entities i.e CRI’s, other universities etc)
Commercial Use: $150/hr
Training Fee of $200 + Geotek time
 iTrax Principal User Use: $100/hr (see list below incl students and collaborators)
Outside Principal Group: $130/hr (non commercial entities i.e CRI’s, other universities etc)
Commercial Use: $250/hr
Training Fee of $200 + iTrax time
 Technician Costs $65/hour for the first 2 categories on both lists</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iTrax XRF Corescanner</title>
      <link>/equipment/itrax/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/equipment/itrax/</guid>
      <description>The Cox Analytical Systems iTrax XRF Corescanner can be used to obtain high resolution geochemical and image data from split drill cores, wet sediments and discrete samples. The itrax has the ability to measure core diameters between 60 and 120mm at resolutions that can range between a minimum of 0.1 mm and a maximum of 10 mm.
The iTrax has the ability to
 measure multiple elements between Al and U in a single run, generally down to ppm levels for most metals.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>